<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Three Dots</title>
  <subtitle>The website of an elliptical human</subtitle>
  <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://threedots.ca"/>
  <updated>2020-11-30T11:30:06.039869-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://threedots.ca</id>
  <author>
    <name>Alan Rempel</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">This is my favourite sentence that starts with ‘and’:</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/jaynesian/"/>
    <updated>2020-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2020-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/jaynesian/</id>
    <content type="html">

&lt;p&gt;This is my favourite sentence that starts with ‘and’:

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  Or else there might be a drug in the laurel that could
  have produced such an Apollonian effect. To test this, I have
  crushed laurel leaves and smoked quantities of them in a pipe and
  felt somewhat sick but no more inspired than usual. &lt;mark&gt;And chewed
  them as well for over an hour, and very distinctly felt more
  and more Jaynesian, alas, than Apollonian.&lt;&#x2f;mark&gt;
&lt;&#x2f;blockquote&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
  — Julian Jaynes, &lt;cite&gt;The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown
    of the Bicameral Mind&lt;&#x2f;cite&gt; (Mariner Books, 1990), 323.
&lt;&#x2f;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2f;figure&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">On chickpeas</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/chickpeas/"/>
    <updated>2020-11-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2020-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/chickpeas/</id>
    <summary>I muse upon my fondness for removing the skin from chickpeas.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whenever I open up and rinse a can of chickpeas, I find myself idly
picking one up and and with two fingers swiftly slipping off its
transparent skin—&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt;and then another—a satisfying sensation: soon I am
engrossed in plucking off each of their slippery coats one by one. I
know I have other things to do—chop sweet potatoes, for instance—my
better judgement protests, but my hands are borne away, unheeding, until
every last chickpea gleams pure &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2f;&#x2f;en.wikipedia.org&#x2f;wiki&#x2f;Chickpea&quot; title=&quot;Chickpea – Wikipedia (Kabuli is the kind of chickpea commonly sold in North America)&quot;&gt;kabuli&lt;&#x2f;a&gt;&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;-yellow, unrefracted by its natal
cloak.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am told that shorn chickpeas make &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2f;&#x2f;smittenkitchen.com&#x2f;2013&#x2f;01&#x2f;ethereally-smooth-hummus&#x2f;&quot; title=&quot;ethereally smooth hummus – smitten kitchen&quot;&gt;the smoothest hummus&lt;&#x2f;a&gt;.
But I do not want the smoothest hummus; I want only to stand at the sink
shelling chickpeas until the sun sets.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">On oomancy</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/oomancy/"/>
    <updated>2020-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/oomancy/</id>
    <summary>In which I reflect upon the inciting incident in my relationship with oomancy.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday evening we had friends over to our apartment for our weekly
oomancy session. As I was sweeping the floor in anticipation of their
arrival, I reflected upon the first time I tried my hand at oomancy.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; Or perhaps, I muse, oomancy tried its hand at me:
I had not intended to use the eggs for divination, but does it not in
retrospect seem possible—even likely—that divination took place?&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—Sorry: Oomancy is divination by means of eggs. &lt;em&gt;Oo&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; means ‘eggs’
(think &lt;em&gt;ovo&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;,  but without the ‘v’), and &lt;em&gt;mancy&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; means ‘, divination by
means of’. Put it together and you have ‘eggs, divination by means of’.
I didn&#x27;t know this either until about two weeks ago.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular morning was my assigned day to bring breakfast to share
after the small religious service that took place in the Student Union
Building early on Wednesday mornings, which I was accustomed to attend
intermittently. I had decided to bring a variation on my family&#x27;s
traditional weekend breakfast: fresh blueberry muffins and medium-boiled
eggs. Unfortunately, I insisted upon the &lt;em&gt;being-fresh&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; of the muffins at
the expense of my presence at the service: that is, I baked them the
morning of, rather than (as would have been sensible) the night before.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arose too late; I measured too carefully; I spent too long whisking
the eggs; the hour to leave for the service passed me by. I said to
myself, “No matter! I shall move with haste and outstrip the passage of
the minutes!” Of course the passage of the minutes was indifferent to my
haste.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—You who are wise in egg-boiling will know that there
is no way to test whether the eggs are done (without cracking the egg open
and thereby destroying the integrity of the boiled-egg experience): the
only way to cook them the way you want to is to time them &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;. You may
also have the wisdom to know what I forgot: namely that a compulsive &lt;em&gt;haste&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;
and a desire to bend the passage of &lt;em&gt;time&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; are inimical to exactitude.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I arrived at the SUB, shuffling in sheepishly to the room
shortly after the service had ended, and set my out breakfast-cargo on
the table. Upon seeing the eggs, my friend remarked that I had brought
no implements with which to crack them: I, to whom, although sympathetic
towards this point, it would never had occurred to bring utensils for
that purpose, could think of no course of action but to demonstrate my
family’s traditional method of egg-cracking, namely, knocking the egg
firmly against the forehead:—and smashed the runny, undercooked egg all
over my face.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my friend&#x27;s part, he told me, his mirth more than made up
for the loss of the eggs. As for me, I was embarrassed and bemused, and
ascribed to the episode no more significance than as a lesson to hallow
the timing of boiling eggs.
Now, though, I am inclined to wonder:
what mystical meaning did this &lt;em&gt;ovum&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; wish to communicate to me? Does a
spiritual residue of its yolk still reside upon my forehead? What might
the science of oomancy have to say about this event? Will I ever see
clearly its true signification?&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">The Rideau Canal</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/rideau-canal/"/>
    <updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/rideau-canal/</id>
    <summary>Basically a fake river.</summary>
    <content type="html">

&lt;p&gt;
As of &lt;time datetime=&quot;2020-06-11&quot;&gt;June 11th&lt;&#x2f;time&gt;, the Rideau Canal in
Ottawa is the nearest body of water to where I live.
Previously it was the Atlantic Ocean; before that, the Assiniboine
River—both natural bodies of water:——but the Rideau Canal is an
artificial one.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; In some respects, the canal seems to want to
imitate the riverhood of its namesake (namely the Rideau River), yet it is patently a
different kind of being entirely. I want to say, for instance, that I have had picnics with
my friends on the bank of the canal, but in truth the
canal has no banks to speak of—just concrete walls bounding it on both sides, each with a
railing on top, and a paved path flush with the top of the wall.
The water is hardly a few inches below the top of the wall—and the soles of one&#x27;s feet.
The canal therefore makes no pretense at having come into being in
concert with its surrounding landscape, as rivers do, e.g. by
gradually carving out a valley for itself.&lt;!--% note 1 %--&gt; On the other hand, it is lined on
each side
along much of its length with a sloping strip of narrow forest,
and beyond this, another paved path, and then a lawn several metres wide (this is what I have in mind when I want to say “we picnicked on the
bank of the canal”):——to me this tree-èd slope suggests aspirations towards
riverhood.&lt;!-- note 2 %--&gt;
It might even engender an illusion of riverhood, if one remains on the grassy area near the
upper path, on the other side of the trees. If, however, one
descends through the trees, down the concrete steps, to the canal-side
pathway, and sees the eerily flat water of the canal, then the illusion
is dissolved.
&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">Jocelyn</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/jocelyn/"/>
    <updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/jocelyn/</id>
    <summary>I recall how I first met Jocelyn.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first met my fiancée on &lt;time datetime=&quot;2017-05-04&quot;&gt;May 4th,
2017&lt;&#x2f;time&gt;.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; I found my record of this incident as I was reading through
my &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;Catalogue of Days&lt;&#x2f;span&gt;, looking for potential blog-post material. (I knew
that we had met in May of that year, but I had forgot the exact date.)
At the time, among my housemates was a good high-school friend of hers,
so she was visiting Halifax for a week and stayed with us. I described her in
that &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;Catalogue&lt;&#x2f;span&gt; entry as &lt;q&gt;pretty cool&lt;&#x2f;q&gt;. (I now have more developed thoughts on
her virtues.)&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">Pen and paper</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/paper-notebook/"/>
    <updated>2020-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/paper-notebook/</id>
    <summary>I muse upon the excellences of paper notebooks, as opposed to electronic programs designed for comparable purposes.
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have started using a paper notebook for an agenda&#x2f;planner&#x2f;to-do-list
thing. It&#x27;s been an interesting experiment. &lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; I notice that I tend to waste all kinds of time
&lt;em&gt;configuring&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; whatever computer program I use, but there is no such thing as that
with the paper notebook, because “configuring” it and using it
are one: both of these consist in writing lines, symbols, and characters with the pen on the page.
You create the scaffolding the same way you create the content. This is
not so with computer-based tools because, while writing prose on a computer is very easy –
a computer even has special hardware designed for it –
organizing that prose &lt;em&gt;visually&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; – as one wants to do when one
is making an agenda (a section of the page for each day of the week, for example) – is vastly more cumbersome.
Some computer-based task-management or calendar-management tools are actually very good – but
they cost at least as much as my notebook did, and I have more confidence that my notebook
will be useful to me, for a long time and in a variety of contexts, than any piece of software.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">I have a secret,</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/secret/"/>
    <updated>2019-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2019-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/secret/</id>
    <summary>Judee Sill has a secret.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a secret, which I’ve never revealed:&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2f;&#x2f;www.youtube.com&#x2f;watch?v=UzrM3eomnAA&quot; title=&quot;Judee Sill&quot;&gt;However we are is okay.&lt;&#x2f;a&gt;&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">This city is a strange place—so much of it is paved.</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/the-trees/"/>
    <updated>2020-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2019-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/the-trees/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This city is a strange place—so much of it is paved.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trees here—it must be lonely for them, not being in a
forest; stretching their roots out and finding soil
compacted by cement, soil sparse of arboreal conversation.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">Holy Communion on Harry Lake</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/holy-communion-on-harry-lake/"/>
    <updated>2019-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2019-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/holy-communion-on-harry-lake/</id>
    <summary>In which it is cold, early morning; mist over the lake; I set my service leaflet on fire.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At this year’s Fall Retreat at Mersey River Chalets, Holy
Communion on the lake took place at 7:00 am, which was later
than in the past – last year I think it was at 6:45. The
temperature had dropped below zero overnight, so the grass
and the leaves upon it were frosty, and there was a thin
layer of ice on the lake, and mist drifting over it. It was
quite beautiful.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had printed leaflets containing the order of worship and
the music for the service, including English Gradual set to
plainchant and hymns. To illuminate these – for it was still
dark outside (although already a little lighter than at 5:30
am, when I had my vigil slot) – we each had a beeswax taper.
I was holding my taper and leaflet in the same hand, in
order to keep my other hand in my pocket for warmth,
switching hands every few minutes.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were singing the Nicene Creed, my friend Sophia,
who was standing beside me, pointed out to me that my
service leaflet was on fire. We both tried to blow it out,
but to no avail – the fire just got bigger. As it was
becoming apparent that my hand would soon get burned if I
did not relinquish the paper, someone – it may have been
Alison, who was standing on my other side – suggested,
either by word or by gesture, I forget which, that I drop it on
the ground and stomp the fire out. I did so, and the fire
was rapidly extinguished.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">My to-do list</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/to-do-list/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2018-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/to-do-list/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a secret to-do list. The problem with my secret
to-do list, though, is that it’s easy for me to forget what
is on it.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; Because it’s not anywhere extant in
writing—that’s how secret it is. If it were recorded
anywhere outside my mind, it wouldn’t be so secret. Even if
were perfectly hidden from the eyes of others, I would
still know where it was and would be tempted to look at it.
So it would be a secret from all others, but not from me.
If it’s not written down, I can’t look at it, and so it can
be a secret from me too—just to the extent that I don’t
remember I have it. But this is the trouble, that in order
to preserve its secrecy, I don’t often call it to mind—or,
I sometimes call to mind individual items that happen to be
on the list, but not often in the context of the list, and
I very rarely think of the list as a whole. And the trouble
is that because of this, I run the risk of forgetting its
structure—and should I forget the structure of the list,
even if I remember, individually and not necessarily at the
same time, each of its items,—then the list is no longer.
Because it exists only in my mind, you see—there’s nothing
and no one else to testify to it.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">Purple sparks</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/purple-sparks/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2018-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/purple-sparks/</id>
    <summary>I ponder with melancholy the continued absence of my purple sparks.</summary>
    <content type="html">

&lt;p&gt;I used to be able to make purple sparks shoot from my
fingertips. I just had to snap my fingers at just the right
angle, with just the right force, when the humidity was just
right, when my hair was tied up in a bun in just the right
way …

&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t done that since about a year and a half ago now.
Am I still capable of it? I don’t know how to tell—short
of doing it again, of course. I haven’t even tried—why
not? I think I’m afraid of finding out for certain that I’ve
lost it. If I don’t even attempt it, then I can still
imagine that I have the power to do it. Then again,
even if I try it—under just the same circumstances
under which I’ve always found success—and fail, that
need not mean I’ve lost my purple sparks permanently.
Perhaps there is some other condition that needed to obtain
which I wasn’t aware of. Or perhaps the sparks will come
back in their own time.
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">This morn­ing,</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2018-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing/</id>
    <summary>A little dance party with my flatmates reminds me of something I wrote a year ago.
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morn­ing, ﬂat­mates and I had a brief dance party in the
liv­ing room. It was a lot of fun—it felt long over­due. It
made me think of &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2f;posts&#x2f;dancing-lawrence-st&quot; title=&quot;In which I have danced&quot;&gt;a note I had writ­ten to my­self about a year ago&lt;&#x2f;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">What do I have in my pockets?</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/pocket-contents/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2018-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/pocket-contents/</id>
    <summary>In which I have to blow my nose.</summary>
    <content type="html">

&lt;p&gt;
A beeswax taper—&lt;br&gt;
A wrapper from a Hershey kiss—&lt;br&gt;
A phone—&lt;br&gt;
A pen—&lt;br&gt;
A tissue—&lt;br&gt;
A recording device (borrowed from a friend)—&lt;br&gt;
A notebook—&lt;br&gt;
A university ID card—&lt;br&gt;
A debit card—&lt;br&gt;
A house key—&lt;br&gt;
Two dollars eighty-five cents—&lt;br&gt;
One of those cards you can peel off of a McDonald’s coffee cup where
once you have seven stickers you get a free drink—&lt;br&gt;
A cork—&lt;br&gt;
A grocery receipt—&lt;br&gt;
An ATM receipt—&lt;br&gt;
Another pen—&lt;br&gt;
An almond—&lt;br&gt;
A pamphlet from a recent Winter Retreat—&lt;br&gt;
A scrap of paper with a poem written on it (”Great Things
Have Happened” by Alden Nolan), and—thank heavens!—&lt;br&gt;
A tissue.
&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">At Mersey River, at a winter retreat, after Compline</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/winter-retreat-after-compline/"/>
    <updated>2018-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2018-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/winter-retreat-after-compline/</id>
    <summary>Eternal praise! eternal praise!</summary>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Two nights ago, after singing Compline across the lake,
after everyone else had dispersed, drifted back either to
the dining hall or to their own cabins: Nick Halley and I
standing on the edge of the frozen lake, looking out and
marveling, and resting alert and in awe, in the company of
the wind and of the snow and of the trees and of each other.
The clouds were moving swiftly across the sky—indistinct
in the darkness, but as they passed within a certain radius
of the moon their outlines were illuminated. The moon’s
light ebbed and grew stronger as clouds came and went in
front of it.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river is &lt;em&gt;marvellous&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;: louder than the wind, unceasing roaring,
a joyous clamour surging from the heart of the Kejimkujik
forest. ‘Eternal praise, eternal praise!’—singing with all
its might …&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">At the Lucky Penny, shortly before noon</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/jack-mitchell/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/jack-mitchell/</id>
    <summary>In which I spy a sometime professor of mine, and am somehow amused.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spotted Jack Mitchell searching the Perseus English-Latin
lexicon for the word ‘virtuous’.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">At Duncan St and Chebucto Lane</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/duncan-st/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/duncan-st/</id>
    <summary>I encounter some children while looking at a tree; they endeavour to sort out my life plans.</summary>
    <content type="html">
&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2f;images&#x2f;a-tree-with-a-face.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tree with a pointy face.&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2f;p&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was walking down Duncan street last Sunday evening, I
came across a tree that that had a face—eyes, a nose and a
mouth affixed to its bark.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; I paused to admire it and take a
picture—but at this point I was accosted by a couple of
children who were hanging out in the yard of the house to my
left. Fortunately, being accosted by children happens to
number among my favourite hobbies. So we struck up a
conversation. They asked me how old I was.—Twenty, I
replied; they asked, as though it followed
naturally,—Are you married?—No, I said.—Why not? they
said. You’re twenty years old, you’re tall, you have long
and luscious hair (perhaps they said ‘flowing’ instead of
‘luscious’, I don’t remember): what are you waiting for?—I
told them that I felt I was in no particular hurry, that I
have so many other things in my life occupying my attention,
and that——Nonsense, they said. Here’s what you should
do. The next girl you see, you go up to her and say, “Hello!
My name is”–what’s your name, again?—Alan.—“Hello! My
name is Alan! Do you want to get married?”—Wouldn’t that
seem a bit abrupt? I said.—I guess so, said the
one.—Hey! said the other, no, do this: The next girl you
see, give her some flowers, and then she’ll like you and ask
&lt;em&gt;you&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; to marry &lt;em&gt;her&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;!—I told them I liked this plan better.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">I was bored this afternoon,</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/garlic/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/garlic/</id>
    <summary>I ate a raw clove of garlic.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was bored this afternoon, so I ate a raw clove of garlic.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">Whatever is nec­es­sary that such dance par­ties as that of last</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing-lawrence-st/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2017-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing-lawrence-st/</id>
    <summary>In which I have danced</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whatever is nec­es­sary
that such dance par­ties as that of last night
should hap­pen again—that’s what mat­ters to me.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; That
everybody should be able to dance with their
friends in a safe and com­fort­able space and know this and dance freely
and en­joy it and have lots of fun, know­ing that they are among
friends—that is what is most worth­while to me.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">On skating</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/skating/"/>
    <updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2017-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/skating/</id>
    <summary>Sometimes I space out for a moment.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While skating at the Oval this afternoon with a few
friends, I felt compelled to offer an explanation for why I
was alternating smooth skating with bouts of stumbling:
“Sometimes I space out for a moment and I’m no
longer in the zone! But I just take a moment to
centre myself and it&#x27;s all right.” My friend thought this
remark expressed a truth about my essence. I think he was
right, but I also think my skates were not laced tightly enough.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">I made a remark shortly after I came in the door—paraphrased</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/parisian-baguette/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2016-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/parisian-baguette/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made a remark shortly after I came in the door—paraphrased from David Lebovitz—about the state of the Parisian baguette: Emma is this moment recording it in her quote-book. I am flattered.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">In the Winnipeg International Airport</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/airport/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <published>2016-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/airport/</id>
    <summary>I set off for Halifax from the Winnipeg airport after the Christmas break, and observe my surroundings and moods.</summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised to find the security area
        virtually deserted.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; The kindly woman standing in front of the
queueing area touched the palms of my hands with a white
hemisphere on the end of a wand and said (having just seen
Paul hug me tight around in circles) how lovely it was to
see such a close-knit family, and wished me a happy new year.
I had to show my boarding pass five times total, three of
those times in the security area. I was the
only one in the x-ray line.&lt;p&gt;—The security staffperson: “No liquids, aerosols, gels,
toiletries, toothpaste, shaving cream, water
bottles?”—I: “No, those things are all in my checked bag.
Well, an empty water bottle.”—”Wait – empty? Does it have
any water in it?”—”No.”—”Okay, then.”&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s ten after eleven and they’re saying the plane
probably won’t arrive for fifteen minutes yet. Guess I’ll go
for another walk or something. A television: the woman on the CBC news
says “we’re so consumeristic, a lot of the things still have
labels in them, the resale market shouldn’t be overlooked.”&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encounter a sign advertising a Chestnut Praline Latte at
Starbucks. I have nothing to do, and am feeling
suggestible; I shall go to the Starbucks and purchase a
chestnut praline latte.—It tastes quite good – a lovely burnt-sugar flavour.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>