<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Three Dots</title>
  <subtitle>The website of Alan Rempel, an elliptical man</subtitle>
  <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://threedots.ca"/>
  <updated>2020-08-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://threedots.ca</id>
  <author>
    <name>Alan Rempel</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>On transit</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/transit/"/>
    <updated>2020-08-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2020-08-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/transit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think about public transit a lot. I think it&#39;s really important, and I
am very interested in how it can be made better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve realized recently that the &lt;em&gt;activity&lt;/em&gt; of riding public
transit, on the other hand, does, in general, not bring me joy.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, why &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; it bring me joy? I wouldn&#39;t expect anyone else to
love it.—In my case, I can think of two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have thought for a long time that transit is very important and good and beneficial.
It seems consonant with these thoughts like being on transit.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; aria-label=&quot;Footnote 1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; One hardly wishes to
think to think when out walking, “Ah, transit is good”, and to think
when on the bus, “Ah, this stupid bus!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For most of my life, I have taken transit only occasionally and
irregularly, and not ususally for trips where I had to be somewhere at
a certain time. This meant that I actually did often enjoy riding
transit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point deserves elaboration. The purpose of my transit trips
have typically been occasional in nature, whether for business or for
leisure. Procuring a provincial ID card, for instance, or going to the
Value Village. Even when the purpose was mundane, the journey often had the flavour
of a special expedition or adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transit part of the trip
contributed to this flavour. Through the windows of the bus
I could see parts of the city that
I had seen before only rarely or not at all. Even some of the navigating and wayfinding
that one has to do—finding the next stop when changing buses, for
example, or orienting oneself upon getting off the bus,——which one might
otherwise find frustrating—becomes part of the adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, my situation has changed, such that I now use transit in a very regular way. I namely have &lt;em&gt;a job&lt;/em&gt; – one that
moreover requires me to go every other day to an office, which seems unusual these days! I don&#39;t mind it;
I am glad to see my boss and my fellow-workers in
person regularly. But I have to take transit to get there. Now my transit trips are no longer mainly occasional
excursions, but regular trips to the same place. The time I must leave at is not determined by my whim, but by
the combination of when I have to be there and the bus schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t really dislike my commutes to work; neither do I enjoy them. The
best part is always the fifteen-minute walk from my house
to &lt;a href=&quot;https://otrain.railfans.ca/confederation-stations/parliament&quot; title=&quot;Parliament Station – O-Train Fans&quot;&gt;the O-Train station&lt;/a&gt;.
After that, I just stand in a train for ten
minutes, wait a bit, and sit on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.octranspo.com/en/plan-your-trip/schedules-maps/?sched-lang=en&amp;amp;date=20200831&amp;amp;rte=50&quot; title=&quot;Route 50 to Lincoln Fields | Schedules and Maps | OC Transpo&quot;&gt;a bus&lt;/a&gt;
for fifteen minutes. The entire trip is about 45
minutes long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The train
ride is certainly very comfortable, and the stations are modern. But the
trip on the whole has no value for me except in that it gets me to my
destination. I would much rather walk for 45 minutes, but that
would not get me to the office. The value of transit for me, then, is
that it gets me there at all while allowing me to get up at a reasonable
hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot is that my experience no longer lets me be confused about
what the value of transit is for me. There is nothing that could
reasonably be more pleasant or convenient about my regular commute. The
only thing that could improve it would be if it were faster, because I
have better things to do than hang out in a bus or train. When I have
enjoyed riding transit in the past, this had more to do with the
character of the trip than with the transit itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that my commute so long as 45 minutes is not the transit
agency&#39;s fault. The issue is that my workplace is in a
neighbourhood&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn3&quot; aria-label=&quot;Footnote 3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that is awkward for transit to serve and generates very
little ridership. My trip to work would be more convenient if the bus I
take came more often (than every half-hour), but its ridership cannot
justify more frequency. This is basically a predictable consequence of
where my workplace is.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; aria-label=&quot;Footnote 2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could make my trip shorter and more pleasant, however, by procuring a
bicycle. That would change everything about my trips to work. I could
leave at the time of my choosing, take the most direct route possible,
and derive a greater degree of pleasure from the experience. Really the
only thing deterring me is that I don&#39;t have a good place to store it. I
think, however, that I do have a very awkward place to store, which may
suffice for as long as I live in my current dwelling.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Rideau Canal</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/rideau-canal/"/>
    <updated>2020-07-07T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2020-07-07T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/rideau-canal/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
As of &lt;time datetime=&quot;2020-06-11&quot;&gt;June 11th&lt;/time&gt;, the Rideau Canal in
Ottawa is the nearest body of water to where I live.
Previously it was the Atlantic Ocean; before that, the Assiniboine
River—both natural bodies of water:——but the Rideau Canal is an
artificial one.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; In some respects, however, the canal seems to want to
imitate the riverhood of its namesake, yet it is patently a
different kind of being entirely. I want to say, for instance, that I have had picnics with
my friends on the bank of the canal, but in truth the
canal has no banks to speak of—just concrete walls bounding it on both sides, each with a
railing on top, and a paved path flush with the top of the wall.
The water is hardly a few inches below the top of the wall—and the soles of one&#39;s feet.
The canal therefore makes no pretense at having come into being in
concert with its surrounding landscape, as rivers do, e.g. by
gradually carving out a valley for itself.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; aria-label=&quot;Footnote 1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; On the other hand, it is lined on
each side
along much of its length with a sloping strip of narrow forest,
and beyond this, another paved path, and then a lawn several metres wide (this is what I have in mind when I want to say “we picnicked on the
bank of the canal”):——to me this tree-èd slope suggests aspirations towards
riverhood.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; aria-label=&quot;Footnote 2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
It might even engender an illusion of riverhood, if one remains on the grassy area near the
upper path, on the other side of the trees. If, however, one
descends through the trees, down the concrete steps, to the canal-side
pathway, and sees the eerily flat water of the canal, then the illusion
is dissolved.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jocelyn</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/jocelyn/"/>
    <updated>2020-05-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2020-05-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/jocelyn/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first met my fiancée on &lt;time datetime=&quot;2017-05-04&quot;&gt;May 4th,
2017&lt;/time&gt;. I found my record of this incident as I was reading through
my &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;Catalogue of Days&lt;/span&gt;, looking for potential blog-post material. (I knew
that we had met in May of that year, but I had forgot the exact date.)
At the time, among my housemates was a good high-school friend of hers,
so she was visiting for a week and stayed with us. I described her in
that entry as &lt;q&gt;pretty cool&lt;/q&gt;. (I now have more developed thoughts on
her virtues.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pen and paper</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/paper-notebook/"/>
    <updated>2020-02-01T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2020-03-16T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-02-01T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/paper-notebook/</id>
    <summary>I muse upon the excellences of paper notebooks, as opposed to electronic programs designed for comparable purposes.
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have started using a paper notebook for an agenda/planner/to-do-list
thing. It&#39;s been an interesting experiment. &lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; I notice that I tend to waste all kinds of time
&lt;em&gt;configuring&lt;/em&gt; whatever computer program I use, but there is no such thing as that
with the paper notebook, because “configuring” it and using it
are one: both of these consist in writing lines, symbols, and characters with the pen on the page.
You create the scaffolding the same way you create the content. This is
not so with computer-based tools because, while writing prose on a computer is very easy –
a computer even has special hardware designed for it –
organizing that prose &lt;em&gt;visually&lt;/em&gt; – as one wants to do when one
is making an agenda (a section of the page for each day of the week, for example) – is vastly more cumbersome.
Some computer-based task-management or calendar-management tools are actually very good – but
they cost at least as much as my notebook did, and I have more confidence that my notebook
will be useful to me, for a long time and in a variety of contexts, than any piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I have a secret, which I’ve never …</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/secret/"/>
    <updated>2019-11-26T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2019-11-26T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/secret/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a secret, which I’ve never revealed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UzrM3eomnAA&quot; title=&quot;Judee Sill&quot;&gt;However we are is okay.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This city is a strange place—so much of …</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/the-trees/"/>
    <updated>2019-11-20T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2020-05-15T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <published>2019-11-20T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/the-trees/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This city is a strange place—so much of it is paved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trees here—it must be lonely for them, not being in a
forest; stretching their roots out and finding soil
compacted by cement, soil sparse of arboreal conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Holy Communion on Harry Lake</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/holy-communion-on-harry-lake/"/>
    <updated>2019-10-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2019-10-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/holy-communion-on-harry-lake/</id>
    <summary>In which it is cold, early morning, misty over the lake, I set my service leaflet on fire.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At this year’s Fall Retreat at Mersey River Chalets, Holy
Communion on the lake took place at 7:00 am, which was later
than in the past – last year I think it was at 6:45. The
temperature had dropped below zero overnight, so the grass
and the leaves upon it were frosty, and there was a thin
layer of ice on the lake, and mist drifting over it. It was
quite beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had printed leaflets containing the order of worship and
the music for the service, including English Gradual set to
plainchant and hymns. To illuminate these – for it was still
dark outside (although already a little lighter than at 5:30
am, when I had my vigil slot) – we each had a beeswax taper.
I was holding my taper and leaflet in the same hand, in
order to keep my other hand in my pocket for warmth,
alternating hands every few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were singing the Nicene Creed, my friend Sophia,
who was standing beside me, pointed out to me that my
service leaflet was on fire. We both tried to blow it out,
but to no avail – the fire just got bigger. As it was
becoming apparent that my hand would soon get burned if I
did not relinquish the paper, someone – it may have been
Alison, who was standing on my other side – suggested,
either by word or by gesture, I forget, that I drop it on
the ground and stomp the fire out. I did so, and the fire
was rapidly extinguished.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My to-do list</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/to-do-list/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-09T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2018-07-09T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/to-do-list/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a secret to-do list. The problem with my secret
to-do list, though, is that it’s easy for me to forget what
is on it.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; Because it’s not anywhere extant in
writing—that’s how secret it is. If it were recorded
anywhere outside my mind, it wouldn’t be so secret. Even if
were perfectly hidden from the eyes of others, I would
still know where it was and would be tempted to look at it.
So it would be a secret from all others, but not from me.
If it’s not written down, I can’t look at it, and so it can
be a secret from me too—just to the extent that I don’t
remember I have it. But this is the trouble, that in order
to preserve its secrecy, I don’t often call it to mind—or,
I sometimes call to mind individual items that happen to be
on the list, but not often in the context of the list, and
I very rarely think of the list as a whole. And the trouble
is that because of this, I run the risk of forgetting its
structure—and should I forget the structure of the list,
even if I remember, individually and not necessarily at the
same time, each of its items,—then the list is no longer.
Because it exists only in my mind, you see—there’s nothing
and no one else to testify to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Purple sparks</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/purple-sparks/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-06T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2018-07-06T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/purple-sparks/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I used to be able to make purple sparks shoot from my
fingertips. I just had to snap my fingers at just the right
angle, with just the right force, when the humidity was just
right, when my hair was tied up in a bun in just the right
way …

&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven’t done that since about a year and a half ago now.
Am I still capable of it? I don’t know how to tell—short
of doing it again, of course. I haven’t even tried—why
not? I think I’m afraid of finding out for certain that I’ve
lost it. If I don’t even attempt it, then I can still
imagine that I have the power to do it. Then again, though,
even if I try it—having found the exact circumstances
under which I’ve always observed succeed—and fail, that
need not mean I’ve lost my purple sparks permanently.
Perhaps there is some other condition that needed to obtain
which I wasn’t aware of. Or perhaps the sparks will come
back in their own time.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This morn­ing, ﬂat­mates and I had a …</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-16T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2018-03-16T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morn­ing, ﬂat­mates and I had a brief dance party in the
liv­ing room. It was a lot of fun–it felt long over­due. It
made me think of &lt;a href=&quot;http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing-lawrence-st&quot; title=&quot;In which I have danced&quot;&gt;a note I had writ­ten to my­self about a year ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What do I have in my pockets?</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/pocket-contents/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-01T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2018-03-01T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/pocket-contents/</id>
    <summary>In which I have to blow my nose.</summary>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
A beeswax taper—&lt;br&gt;
A wrapper from a Hershey kiss—&lt;br&gt;
A phone—&lt;br&gt;
A pen—&lt;br&gt;
A tissue—&lt;br&gt;
A recording device (borrowed from a friend)—&lt;br&gt;
A notebook—&lt;br&gt;
A university ID card—&lt;br&gt;
A debit card—&lt;br&gt;
A house key—&lt;br&gt;
Two dollars eighty-five cents—&lt;br&gt;
One of those cards you can peel off of a McDonald’s coffee cup where
once you have seven stickers you get a free drink—&lt;br&gt;
A cork—&lt;br&gt;
A grocery receipt—&lt;br&gt;
An ATM receipt—&lt;br&gt;
Another pen—&lt;br&gt;
An almond—&lt;br&gt;
A pamphlet from a recent Winter Retreat—&lt;br&gt;
A scrap of paper with a poem written on it (”Great Things
Have Happened” by Alden Nolan), and—thank heavens!—&lt;br&gt;
A tissue.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>At Mersey River, at a winter retreat, after Compline</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/winter-retreat-after-compline/"/>
    <updated>2018-02-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2018-02-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/winter-retreat-after-compline/</id>
    <summary>Eternal praise! eternal praise!</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two nights ago, after singing Compline across the lake,
after everyone else had dispersed, drifted back either to
the dining hall or to their own cabins: Nick Halley and I
standing on the edge of the frozen lake, looking out and
marveling, and resting alert and in awe, in the company of
the wind and of the snow and of the trees and of each other.
The clouds were moving swiftly across the sky—indistinct
in the darkness, but as they passed within a certain radius
of the moon their outlines were illuminated. The moon’s
light ebbed and grew stronger as clouds came and went in
front of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river is &lt;em&gt;marvellous&lt;/em&gt;: louder than the wind, unceasing roaring,
a joyous clamour surging from the heart of the Kejimkujik
forest. ‘Eternal praise, eternal praise!’—singing with all
its might …&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>At the Lucky Penny, shortly before noon</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/jack-mitchell/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-12T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2017-06-12T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/jack-mitchell/</id>
    <summary>In which I spy a sometime professor of mine, and am somehow amused.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spotted Jack Mitchell searching the Perseus English-Latin
lexicon for the word ‘virtuous’.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>At Duncan St and Chebucto Lane</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/duncan-st/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-09T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2017-06-09T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/duncan-st/</id>
    <summary>In which some children endeavour to sort out my life plans.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/a-tree-with-a-face.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tree with a pointy face.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was walking down Duncan street last Sunday evening, I
came across a tree that that had a face—eyes, a nose and a
mouth affixed to its bark. I paused to admire it and take a
picture—but at this point I was accosted by a couple of
children who were hanging out in the yard of the house to my
left. Fortunately, being accosted by children happens to
number among my favourite hobbies.&lt;!-- FOLD --&gt; So we struck up a
conversation. They asked me how old I was.—Twenty, I
replied; they asked, as though it followed
naturally,—Are you married?—No, I said.—Why not? they
said. You’re twenty years old, you’re tall, you have long
and luscious hair (perhaps they said ‘flowing’ instead of
‘luscious’, I don’t remember): what are you waiting for?—I
told them that I felt I was in no particular hurry, that I
have so many other things in my life occupying my attention,
and that——Nonsense, they said. Here’s what you should
do. The next girl you see, you go up to her and say, “Hello!
My name is”–what’s your name, again?—Alan.—“Hello! My
name is Alan! Do you want to get married?”—Wouldn’t that
seem a bit abrupt? I said.—I guess so, said the
one.—Hey! said the other, no, do this: The next girl you
see, give her some flowers, and then she’ll like you and ask
&lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; to marry &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt;!—I told them I liked this plan better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I was bored this afternoon, so I ate a …</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/garlic/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-08T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2017-06-08T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/garlic/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was bored this afternoon, so I ate a raw clove of garlic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Having danced</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing-lawrence-st/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-04T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <updated>2017-05-04T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/dancing-lawrence-st/</id>
    <summary>In which I have danced</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whatever is nec­es­sary
that such dance par­ties as that of last night
should hap­pen again—that’s what mat­ters to me. That
everybody should be able to dance with their
friends in a safe and com­fort­able space and know this and dance freely
and en­joy it and have lots of fun, know­ing that they are among
friends—that is what is most worth­while to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>While skating at the Oval this afternoon …</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/skating/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2017-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/skating/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While skating at the Oval this afternoon with a few
friends, I felt compelled to offer an explanation for why I
was alternating smooth skating with bouts of stumbling:
“Sometimes I space out for a moment and suddenly I’m no
longer in the zone! But it’s okay, I just take a moment to
center myself and get back in the groove.” My friend thought this
remark expressed a truth about my essence. I think he was
right; also, I am sure my skates were not laced tightly enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I made a remark shortly after I came in …</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/parisian-baguette/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-14T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2016-12-14T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/parisian-baguette/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made a remark shortly after I came in the door—paraphrased from David Lebovitz—about the state of the Parisian baguette: Emma is this moment recording it in her quote-book. I am flattered.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>In the Winnipeg International Airport</title>
    <link href="http://threedots.ca/posts/airport/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-10T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <updated>2016-01-10T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://threedots.ca/posts/airport/</id>
    <summary>Setting off for Halifax; musing; killing time.</summary>
    <content type="html">      &lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised to find the security area was
virtually deserted. The kindly woman standing before the
queueing area touched the palms of my hands with the white
hemisphere on the end of a wand and said (having just seen
Paul hug me tight around in circles) how lovely it was to
see such a close-knit family and wished me a happy new year.
I had to show my boarding pass five times total, three of
those in the security area. I was the
only one in the x-ray line.—The security line staffperson: “No liquids, aerosols, gels,
toiletries, toothpaste, shaving cream, water
bottles?”—I: “No, those things are all in my checked bag.
Well, an empty water bottle.”—”Wait – empty? Does it have
any water in it?”—”No.”—”Okay, then.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s ten after eleven and they’re saying the plane
probably won’t arrive for fifteen minutes yet. Guess I’ll go
for another walk or something. The woman on the CBC news
says “we’re so consumeristic, a lot of the things still have
labels in them, the resale market shouldn’t be overlooked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encounter a sign advertising a Chestnut Praline Latte at
Starbucks. I have nothing to do, and I am feeling
suggestible; I shall go to the Starbucks and purchase a
chestnut praline latte.—It tastes quite good – a lovely burnt-sugar flavour.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
